Animation Number 1
Failing memories and recollections.
So in the end, we don't know exactly what the "darkness" is.
（阿良々木(あららぎ)）“くらやみ”の正体は
最終的に分からずじまい
ということなんだな
Indeed, we don't know what it is.
（忍(しのぶ)）分からずじまい… じゃな
Honestly, I couldn't do anything against the "darkness" even back in my prime.
“くらやみ”に対して
全盛期のわしでも
打つ手はなかったというのが
正直なところじゃが
I doubt that has changed since then. Now, what to do...
そんなことは
言っておれんじゃろうな
さて どうしたものか
Mystery
Animation Number 23
A mystery inviting mysteries.
But it didn't chase you 400 years ago, right?
Animation Number 23
A mystery inviting mysteries.
（阿良々木）
でも 400年前は
A mystery inviting mysteries.
Animation Number 23
Darkness
Animation Number 24
追って
こなかったんだろ？
Maybe after we managed to escape, that's it.
じゃあ 今回も
こうして
逃げきったところで
おしまいって可能性も…
That may be true, but that may not be true.
そうかもしれんが
そうでないかもしれんじゃろうが
We need countermeasures, and if possible, I'd like to strike first.
対策は打たねばならんし
できれば
こちらから攻撃したいくらいじゃ
Yellow Scene
Animation Number 'none'
If all the residents of this area are spirited away, it'll be too late.
この辺りの住人が全て
神隠しに遭ってからでは
遅いじゃろう？
Right.
Animation Number 31
It's not just our problem. This town...  Those who live where I was born and raised...
（阿良々木）
僕や忍だけの問題では済まない
この町…
僕が生まれ育った
この町の住人が
Senjougahara Hitagi
Animation Number 33
I have to act, or else everyone could end up missing.
Senjougahara Hitagi
Animation Number 33
全員 失踪してしまう
というケースを想定して
Senjougahara Hitagi
Animation Number 33
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Kanbaru Suruga
Animation Number 33
Sengoku Nadeko
Araragi Karen
Animation Number 33
Araragi Tsukihi
行動しなければ
ならないのだ
For now, when Hachikuji wakes up, we can explain things and split up to start a full effort to...
（忍）とりあえず
八九寺(はちくじ)が目を覚ましたら
事情を説明し
そして 別れて本格的に行動を…
（斧乃木(おののき)）
それは やめておいたほうが
いいんじゃないかな
I don't think you should do that, devil boy.
鬼のおにいちゃん
She wedges between us like a bookmark.
Animation Number 44
Ononoki-chan...
（阿良々木）斧乃木ちゃん
You shouldn't believe everything that hag says. If you act how she wants, you'll see lots of trouble.
（斧乃木）
そんな後期高齢者の言い分を
うのみにして
その口車に乗って行動したら
えらい目に遭うよ
I feel gratitude for you buying me ice cream.
鬼のおにいちゃんには
アイスクリームを
おごってもらった恩があるからね
I can't watch you be tricked by a foolish aberration and end up in a terrible mess, so I'll warn you.
愚かな怪異(かいい)に唆されて
ひどい目に遭うのを
看過はできないから
忠告しておく
Lots of talking involved.
Animation Number 51
うん 話は全て聞かせてもらった
Yeah. I heard the entire story. By chance.
偶然
（忍）フンッ
Hmph!
I didn't think you'd still have the nerve to call me a hag to my face, tsukumo-gami girl.
わしを“後期高齢者”と
面と向かって まだ呼ぶ度胸が
残っておったとは意外じゃったぞ
付喪神(つくもがみ)娘
You're scared and trembling inside anyway.
どうせ内心 震えておるくせにの
In light of your courage, I'll spare you from being eaten to death this instant.
その度胸に免じて特別に
今 この場で 一瞬で
食い殺すことだけは勘弁してやろう
We'll see. Wouldn't that be hard in your current state?
（斧乃木）どうかな
今のあなたには
難しいんじゃないのかな
どうしてもと言うのなら
If you insist, I'll play along with you...
相手になってあげないことも
ないけど… ね
All right?
Hmph, a rematch?
（忍）フンッ 再戦か
H-Hey, stop it, both of you.
（阿良々木）
お… おい やめろよ お前ら
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
それよりも斧乃木ちゃん
Or rather, Ononoki-chan...
What?
（斧乃木）何？
（阿良々木）いや…
I mean, why'd you go and stand in the hallway? You didn't have to lie that you had work.
（阿良々木）
なんで わざわざ廊下に
控えるようなまねをしたんだ？
仕事があるなんて
ウソをついてまで
The part about me having work wasn't a lie. I just delayed my plans a bit.
（斧乃木）
仕事があるというのは
ウソじゃないよ
ちょっと予定を遅らせただけだ
Well, that old hag there is pretty narrow-minded. I thought she might hesitate to talk if I was here.
なに そこの後期高齢者は
人格が狭量だからね
僕が この場にいたら
話を渋るんじゃないかと思って
おいおい 見誤るなよ
Hey, hey, don't misunderstand me. Do I look like such an intolerant person?
わしが
そんな小さい人間に見えるか？
（阿良々木）う…
You do
Animation Number 87
Shinobu Time         Part Three
Font used in the video: HGP Mincho B
（忍）うがっ！
Oh no! She caught me off guard!
（阿良々木）
しまった… 油断した！
Now's the time! Get her!
（忍）今じゃ お前様！
やっちまえ！
Don't assume I'll be an accomplice.
僕が共犯者であることを
前提にすんな
You can fondle her breasts!
（忍）胸！　もみ放題じゃぞ
No, stuff like that isn't a turn-on if it's not one-on-one...
いや… そういう行為は
１対１でないと
萌(も)えないから
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
When I think about it, this is a very dreamlike situation. First off, I'm in this classroom. And around me I have...
しかし これ 考えてみれば
夢のような状況だな
教室の中に まず 僕がいて
そして その周囲に
A girl, a young girl, and a little girl.
少女と 幼女と 童女がいる
What is this place, Shangri-La?
なんだ ここは
ひょっとして桃源郷か？
You realize you're speaking every thought you're having?
お前様 考えとることが全部
セリフになっとるぞ
Whoa, that was close. Barely safe.
（阿良々木）おっと 危ない危ない
ギリギリセーフ
True, that statement cut it close...
確かに発言はギリギリじゃったが…
Demon
Corpse
Snail
Who would've thought a plot development would put them in one place? It's a wonderful bonus stage!
（阿良々木）
この三者が
一堂に会するなんて展開を
一体 誰が想像するだろう
すばらしいボーナスステージだ
He's grinning about something.
なにか鬼のおにいちゃんが
ニヤニヤしているよ
That's how he is.
（忍）そういう男じゃ
Careful. He's the type that stalks you for the rest of your life after one kiss.
気をつけろよ
１回 キスしたくらいで
生涯 付きまとうタイプの男じゃぞ
Oh, my
I wager they're making me out to be the bad guy now.
Animation Number 113
By the way, since we have the opportunity, let's make something clear.
ところで
せっかくの機会じゃから お前様
ここらで はっきりしておこうか
Who do you like most among the three of us?
この３人の中で
誰が いちばん好きなのじゃ？
（阿良々木）え？
（斧乃木）そうだね
Oh gosh!
Animation Number 118
True. We should have that made clear.
それは はっきり
させておかないと
This is a disaster.
Animation Number 119
U-Um, if I had to pick among the three here...
（阿良々木）
えっ えっと…
この３人の中でって
言われると
そりゃ もちろん
...of course it'd be my one and the same, my partner, Shinobu.
一心同体であり
パートナーである
First   Oshino Shinobu
Animation Number 131
忍 お前のことが…
First   Oshino Shinobu
Animation Number 131
You...
I'd like to hear what you'd think if we weren't one and the same, or partners.
（忍）一心同体でなく
パートナーでなければという場合の
答えを聞きたいのう
I'm getting cornered.
Animation Number 135
Damn this scene.
This is clearly venting. Nothing more than harassing me!
（阿良々木）
こんなの明らかに八つ当たり
嫌がらせ以外の何でもない
No, while we're at it, rather than we three...
（忍）
いやいや この際
この場におる３人というより
Between me, Ms. Tsundere, and Cat Class Prez...
わしと ツンデレ娘と
猫委員長との
３人の中から
What you should tell us is who you would pick from those.
誰か１人 選ぶなら
誰？
Who
Animation Number 137
という話を
してしまおうか
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Before that, Ononoki-chan, what did you think of Shinobu's story?
そんなことより 斧乃木ちゃん
忍の話を聞いて どう思った？
She said she had no idea what the "darkness" was, but were you able to think of something by association?
“くらやみ”について 心当たりは
全くないってことだったけれど
しかし 忍の話から
何か連想できたことが
あったんじゃないか？
"Before that"?
そんなことより？
Is the issue of who you like most something that you can dismiss just like that?
鬼のおにいちゃんにとって
誰が いちばん好きかというのは
“そんなこと”で
済まされてしまうことなのかい？
（阿良々木）むにゃ
（八九寺）むにゃ
Where am I?
ここは… どこでしょう
（阿良々木）あっ…
Animation Number 148
Hachikuji!
はちくじいいいい！
わああ〜！
Hachikuji screaming
Animation Number 167
It's been way too long since I last heard this
It's like Mozart to my ears
Animation Number 167
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Thank goodness! You're awake?
（阿良々木）
よかった！　目が覚めたのか
You were totally out, so I thought you got hit somewhere bad or were beyond the point of no return.
お前 気絶したっきり
全然 起きないから
打ち所が悪かったんじゃないか…
取り返しのつかないことに
なったんじゃないかと
気が気でなかったんだ
You had me so worried! But I'm so glad you woke up all right!
でも よかった！
ちゃんと目を覚まして
（八九寺）うわああ…
（阿良々木）ええい！
Damn it, let me touch you more! Let me lick you more! Let me suck on you more!
（阿良々木）もっと触らせろ
もっとなめさせろ
もっと吸わせろ〜！
がうっ！
（阿良々木）くう〜
They bit me.
Animation Number 176
This is Heaven on Earth.
どわあ！
Stop fooling around! What do you think you're doing right in front of me, fool!
（忍）ふざけんな！　お前様
わしが出てきとる前で
堂々と何をやっとんじゃボケ！
I just joined in.
（斧乃木）
僕は まあ なんとなくノリで
I'm getting assaulted.
Animation Number 177
A masochist's paradise.
You could call it abuse.
Animation Number 177
Well, you have to.
W-Wait, you guys!
（阿良々木）ま… 待て お前たち
I understand your feelings, but calm down! Is now the time?
気持ちは分かるが 落ち着け！
今 こんなことをしてる場合か？
Anybody could have told them
Animation Number 181
as long as it wasn't me
フウ…
By the way, Hachikuji, are you really okay? The examination didn't reveal anything just now.
ところで 八九寺
本当に大丈夫か？
今 触診した感じだと
大事なさそうだが
Are you a doctor?
医者ですか あなたは
Pink Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I'm fine. Nothing's wrong!
大丈夫です　問題ありません
All okay! All green! It's perfect!
オールオッケー オールグリーン
パーフェクトです
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
In the first place, I didn't find that unknown thing to be a problem at all, Araragi-san.
もともと あんな正体不明
私は
まるっきり問題にしていませんよ
阿良々木さん
You sure were flustered before.
Animation Number 190
Guess this shows the strength of your spirit.
But I will say thanks, Araragi-san.
しかし 礼を言いますよ
阿良々木さん
Come on, they do say "good fences make good neighbors," but we don't need stuff like that between us.
親しき仲にも礼儀あり
とはいうけれど
僕とお前の間には
そんな水くさいもん いらねえよ
No, it wasn't for the hug earlier. I thanked you for not abandoning me and for escaping from that thing with me.
いえ… 先ほどの
ハグについてのことではなく
私を見捨てずに
一緒に逃走してくれたことに
お礼を言ったのです
I had thought in situations like that...
ああいう場合
てっきり 阿良々木さんは
Light Green Scene
Animation Number 'none'
...you would just shake me off and escape to safety by yourself.
私のことなど振り落として
自分だけ逃げると思っていました
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Zero confidence!
（阿良々木）
うわ〜い 信用ゼロだ！
Holy hell.
Animation Number 199
Besides, I was also happy you didn't ignore the red light.
（八九寺）それに…
信号無視をしないでくれたのも
うれしかったです
You were being considerate to me, right?
あれは私に
気を遣ってくれたんですよね？
Hachikuji.
八九寺…
I wouldn't have minded if you ignored it.
まあ 別に されても
私 気にしませんけどね
I'm not that high-strung.
そんな神経質じゃないですし
I'm so disappointed in you!
がっかりだよ！　お前には
No.
Animation Number 204
We did run some red lights.
And we received divine punishment.
Animation Number 204
Now, everyone! Now that I'm awake, let's switch gears. Get this, Shinobu-san, Ononoki-san.
さあ 皆さん！
私が目を覚ましたところで
切り替えていきましょう
いいですか？　忍さん 斧乃木さん
I respect your individuality, but this one time, I beg you to not fall out of step.
お二人の個性は尊重しますけれど
今回ばかりは
足並みを乱さずに お願いしますよ
Today's the day our teamwork will be tested.
今日は私たちのチームワークが
試される日です
S-Sure.
（忍）は… はい！
（斧乃木）うん
Somehow Hachikuji's in the lead, and the other two are following.
（阿良々木）
なぜか 八九寺が仕切り
Koyomi   Monologue / Thoughts
Animation Number 209
なぜか ２人が従った
Koyomi   Monologue / Thoughts
Animation Number 209
（パン パン！）
Then, Code Name Gold, situation report please.
（八九寺）
では コードネームゴールド
現在の状況を述べてください
（忍）はい！
Okay!
Hey! That's probably enough from you.
て… おい！
うぬ さすがに いいかげんにしろよ
I'll eat you soon enough.
Thus ends Hachikuji's short-lived reign.
Animation Number 213
食うぞ
フッ あなたに私が
食べられますかねえ
Can you really eat me?
She's hinting at more power than she has.
Animation Number 216
Like she's harboring a Leucochloridium worm.
Ultimate Protection
Animation Number 216
About what you said earlier...
（斧乃木）
鬼のおにいちゃん
さっきの話だけど
（阿良々木）え？
If you want something of me, then just kiss me to get my attention, you shy little girl.
Animation Number 218
Earlier?
さっきの話って？
About whether I had a clue.
（斧乃木）心当たりの話
About whether or not I thought of something after hearing that old hag's story.
後期高齢者の話を聞いて
何か新しく思い当たったことが
あるんじゃないかって話だけど
Koyomi   Voice / Speech
Animation Number 220
Ononoki-chan...
Koyomi   Voice / Speech
Animation Number 220
（阿良々木）
斧乃木ちゃん
Koyomi   Voice / Speech
Animation Number 220
Sorry, but can you honestly stop calling Shinobu an old hag already?
悪いけども
忍のことを後期高齢者って呼ぶのを
ここらで ホントに
やめてもらえないか？
In the first place, society is behaving as if that term never existed.
大体 その後期高齢者って言葉も
今 世間では なかったことに
なりつつあるはずなんだから
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Then what should I call her?
じゃあ 何て呼べばいいの？
Devil girl?
“鬼のおねえちゃん”とか？
Shinobu - 8 years old.
Animation Number 223
Mayoi - 10 years old.
Ononoki - 12 years old.
Animation Number 223
Then say Aberration Killer.
じゃあ “怪異殺し”にしとけ
Aberration Slayer
Animation Number 224
Formerly
Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 224
Formerly
Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 224
Formerly
Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 224
Formerly
Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 224
Formerly
Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 224
Oshino Shinobu
Currently
Animation Number 224
Oshino Shinobu
Currently
Animation Number 224
Oshino Shinobu
Currently
Animation Number 224
Oshino Shinobu
Currently
Animation Number 224
Oshino Shinobu
Currently
Animation Number 224
Oshino Shinobu
Currently
Animation Number 224
Oshino Shinobu
Currently
Animation Number 224
Oshino Shinobu
Currently
Animation Number 224
Oshino Shinobu
Currently
Animation Number 224
フウ… しかたない
I guess I have no choice. For now, I'll let devil boy save face.
ここは鬼のおにいちゃんの顔を
立てておいてあげるか
Is her existence as an artifact spirit prompting that frustration?
Animation Number 227
Then let me state my conclusion after hearing Aberration Killer's story by chance...
で その怪異殺しの話を
偶然 立ち聞きしてしまった結果の
結論を言わせてもらうけれど
Yeah, did you think of something?
（阿良々木）
ああ 何か思いついたか？
Mysteries invite more mysteries
Animation Number 229
and only despair grows
That's how it is
Animation Number 229
That isn't an aberration. It's something else.
あれは怪異じゃない
怪異以外の何かだよ
So Aberration Killer and the so-called original Aberration Killer couldn't deal with it.
だからこそ 怪異殺しも
そして 初代怪異殺しとやらも
対応できなかった
Of course not, since different rules moved it.
違うルールで
動いているものなんだから
当たり前だ
Naturally, you won't be able to either.
もちろん 鬼のおにいちゃんにも
対応できないのさ
Animation Number 235
However...
If it isn't an aberration, what is it? That "darkness"... Exactly what is it then?
怪異じゃないなら 何なんだ？
あの“くらやみ”は
一体 “何”ってことになるんだよ
Like darkness itself.
Animation Number 235
It's a mystery.
I don't know its specific name, but I do know someone who does.
具体的な名前は知らない
ただし
それを知っている人は知っている
Then who knows the truth about that "darkness"?
誰が知ってるんだ？
あの“くらやみ”の正体を
Gaen Izuko.
臥煙伊豆湖(がえんいずこ)
Gaen Izuko
Animation Number 238
She knows everything.
彼女は何でも知っている
Animation Number 242
Soon it was there.
Animation Number 243
Quickly it came.
The darkness was there.
Animation Number 243
Hachikuji Mayoi,
Animation Number 244
Oshino Shinobu,
Animation Number 245
Ononoki-chan,
Animation Number 246
and I
Animation Number 247
were afraid.
Animation Number 248
Speechless—
We'd let our guard down.
Animation Number 248
Let's escape, everyone!
逃げますよ 皆さん！
（阿良々木）おう！
Yeah!
Run away?
Animation Number 250
But how?
How can we escape?
Animation Number 251
Right?
Aye.
Animation Number 251
Hachikuji!
八九寺！
Void
Come over here!
こっちに来い！
Hachikuji has to make it, even if nobody else does.
Animation Number 256
So I hope the darkness
comes in my direction.
Animation Number 256
O-Okay!
は… はい！
She must survive.
Animation Number 260
Void
Ononoki-chan! Now!
斧乃木ちゃん 今だ！
Wha... You're too daring.
Void
大胆すぎるよ 鬼のおにいちゃん
Stop that. Don't touch me in weird places. What are you thinking?
やめてよ もう
変な所 触らないで
こんなときに 何 考えてんの？
You're the one thinking weird thoughts!
何 考えてんのは お前だ！
We're escaping, Ononoki-chan! Like before!
逃げるんだよ 斧乃木ちゃん
さっきみたいに！
Void
Oh, that's what you mean...
（斧乃木）ああ そういうこと
Void
Unlimited Rulebook.
アンリミテッド･ルールブック
Void
Unlimited Rulebook
Animation Number 275
Void
Secession version.
離脱版
Animation Number 278
22nd of August
（阿良々木）
ハッ… ここは どこなんだ？
Where are we?
I don't know where this is, devil boy.
（斧乃木）
どこなのかは分からないよ
鬼のおにいちゃん
In the blink of an eye——
Animation Number 283
It's not following us? That "darkness"...
（阿良々木）
追って… きてないのか？
あの“くらやみ”は
It seems not. Well, it seems true that it's weak against vertical movement.
（斧乃木）そうみたいだね
いや 上下の変化に弱いというのは
確かみたいだ
Aberration Killer escaped it that way 400 years ago, so it was good that we jumped vertically again.
怪異殺しも 400年前
そうやって逃走したんだから
今回も上向きに飛んだから
よかったんだ
I am thrilled I did not fall.
Animation Number 287
（阿良々木）
て… 八九寺は どうした？
Where's Hachikuji? I hope she wasn't thrown off.
まさか振り落とされたんじゃ
She's fine. You had a firm grip on her breasts.
（斧乃木）
大丈夫だよ
鬼のおにいちゃんが…
彼女の胸を
がっしり つかんでいたからね
She's sleeping under that tree.
あっちの木陰で寝てる
Animation Number 292
She sure has an attitude when there's no danger.
Relax.
Animation Number 292
What time is it now? Or rather, how long was I passed out?
今 何時なんだ？
ていうか 僕は どれくらいの間
気絶してたんだ？
For how long? Long enough to be toyed around by both me and Hachikuji-san.
どれくらいの間かといえば
僕と八九寺さんとに いいように
遊ばれているくらいの間だよ
What'd you do while I was out?
気絶中の僕に何をした！
Lilac Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Wait, Hachikuji-san? When'd you get friendly?
（阿良々木）
ていうか“八九寺さん”って
なに 仲良くなってんだよ
Specifically, one evening. You were out since twilight, so roughly 12 hours or so.
（斧乃木）具体的には ひと晩だよ
夕方から ずっとだから
まあ およそ12時間ってところかな
12 hours...
（阿良々木）12時間…
I sure slept a long time.
Animation Number 299
A word of caution. The rule that it can't chase us vertically is only theoretical.
（斧乃木）用心して言っておくと
上下移動なら
追ってこないという法則も
思えば経験則でしかないからね
After all, it's "for now." It's not guaranteed next time.
所詮 “今のところ”だ
次も うまくいくとは限らない
Right. Theory aside, I can't figure out the rules for that "darkness" at all.
ああ… 経験則は ともかく
あの“くらやみ”
法則が全くつかめない
What is it?
何なんだ あれ
I'd prefer it chased us, then.
Animation Number 300
How's Hachikuji?
八九寺は？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Purple Scene
Hachikuji was the very image of healthy.
Animation Number 304
My hands have confirmed it.
Animation Number 305
Perfectly Healthy
Animation Number 306
Now, what to do...
さて…
どうしたもんかな
We don't even know where this is...
ここが どこかさえ
分からないっていうんだから
No reception, unsurprisingly——
Animation Number 309
I'd like to retaliate in some way, but can we do so effectively?
反撃に打って出たいところだけど
あれに反撃なんて有効なのか？
First of all, I'm not sure whether it's really after us.
そもそも あれが本当に
僕たちを狙っているのかどうかも
本当は怪しい
Saying it's after Shinobu is nothing more than a theory.
忍を狙っているというのも
経験則といえば経験則だしな
Forming the basis of retaliation requires you to ask.
反撃の基準としては
まずは聞くことだろうね
Ask?
（阿良々木）聞く？
（斧乃木）情報収集だよ
Gather information. Did you forget what I was telling you right before it appeared?
（斧乃木）
あいつが現れる寸前まで
僕がしていた話を忘れたの？
I told you someone knows about the phenomenon that isn't an aberration, right?
あの怪異ならぬ現象を
知っている人がいるって
言っただろう？
She wedges between us like a bookmark.
Animation Number 44
I wager they're making me out to be the bad guy now.
Animation Number 113
That was brutal!
Animation Number 115
This is a disaster.
Animation Number 116
Hachikuji's scream.
Animation Number 117
She's completely beaten up.
Animation Number 118
Anybody could have told them
Animation Number 119
Putting up that much of a fight,
Animation Number 120
I can't believe it.
Animation Number 122
Her three days of supremacy are over.
Animation Number 123
I have a strong feeling she's hiding something.
Animation Number 124
If you want something of me, then just kiss me to get my attention, you shy little girl.
Animation Number 125
Aberration Slayer
Animation Number 224
Is her existence as an artifact spirit prompting that frustration?
Animation Number 227
It's like darkness itself.
Animation Number 236
Gaen Izuko
Animation Number 238
Gaen...
臥煙…
Gaen Izuko. I need to ask her about this. She's acquaintances with Kagenui-san, right?
（阿良々木）
臥煙伊豆湖…
その人に話を聞けばいいのか
影縫(かげぬい)さんの知り合い…
なんだよな？
If so, then for our route, I need to approach Kagenui-san first.
とすると まずはルートとして
影縫さんにアプローチを
取らなければならないのか
Ononoki-chan, are you caught up on work?
（阿良々木）
斧乃木ちゃん
仕事のほうは いいのかい？
Of course not. But I can't readily go back to work right now.
（斧乃木）いいわけないだろ
でも さすがに ここで
あっさりと仕事には戻れないさ
I'm not that cold-hearted.
僕も
そこまで非情じゃあない
Can you contact Kagenui-san?
影縫さんと
連絡を取ることはできる？
It's my last resort, but I do have several ways to access her.
（斧乃木）奥の手として
いくつか おねえちゃんに
アクセスする方法はあるけれど
Though all are impossible in the mountains.
その全てが
今 この山奥では不可能だね
You can't use telepathy?
（阿良々木）
テレパシーで
通じ合えたりしないのか？
Unfortunately, our bond isn't that strong.
（斧乃木）
あいにく 僕たちの絆は
そこまで強くない
We'd have to go down this mountain and approach her by calling or texting.
山を下りて 電話なりメールなりで
アプローチするしかないよ
——But,
Animation Number 322
if things go wrong,
she will abandon me without a second thought.
Animation Number 322
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Or rather, devil boy... Can you pull Aberration Killer out of your shadow already?
と… いうかさ 鬼のおにいちゃん
怪異殺しのヤツを
そろそろ いいかげん
影から引っ張り出してくれないかな
Huh?
Animation Number 325
I don't know if she doesn't want to talk to me or if she's taking a nap,
僕と話すのが嫌なのか
それとも のんきに寝てやがるのか
but she hasn't shown up since we landed here.
ここに着地してから
一向に出てこないんだよ
That reminds me that she isn't here—
no, I was aware that she
wasn't around the entire time.
That's why I assumed
she was in my shadow—
unlike Ononoki or Hachikuji,
Shinobu and I can
never be truly apart.
Animation Number 326
That reminds me that she isn't here—
no, I was aware that she
wasn't around the entire time.
That's why I assumed
she was in my shadow—
unlike Ononoki or Hachikuji,
Shinobu and I can
never be truly apart.
Animation Number 326
That reminds me that she isn't here—
no, I was aware that she
wasn't around the entire time.
That's why I assumed
she was in my shadow—
unlike Ononoki or Hachikuji,
Shinobu and I can
never be truly apart.
Animation Number 326
That reminds me that she isn't here—
no, I was aware that she
wasn't around the entire time.
That's why I assumed
she was in my shadow—
unlike Ononoki or Hachikuji,
Shinobu and I can
never be truly apart.
Animation Number 326
That reminds me that she isn't here—
no, I was aware that she
wasn't around the entire time.
That's why I assumed
she was in my shadow—
unlike Ononoki or Hachikuji,
Shinobu and I can
never be truly apart.
Animation Number 326
That reminds me that she isn't here—
no, I was aware that she
wasn't around the entire time.
That's why I assumed
she was in my shadow—
unlike Ononoki or Hachikuji,
Shinobu and I can
never be truly apart.
Animation Number 326
That reminds me that she isn't here—
no, I was aware that she
wasn't around the entire time.
That's why I assumed
she was in my shadow—
unlike Ononoki or Hachikuji,
Shinobu and I can
never be truly apart.
Animation Number 326
That reminds me that she isn't here—
no, I was aware that she
wasn't around the entire time.
That's why I assumed
she was in my shadow—
unlike Ononoki or Hachikuji,
Shinobu and I can
never be truly apart.
Animation Number 326
That reminds me that she isn't here—
no, I was aware that she
wasn't around the entire time.
That's why I assumed
she was in my shadow—
unlike Ononoki or Hachikuji,
Shinobu and I can
never be truly apart.
Animation Number 326
That reminds me that she isn't here—
no, I was aware that she
wasn't around the entire time.
That's why I assumed
she was in my shadow—
unlike Ononoki or Hachikuji,
Shinobu and I can
never be truly apart.
Animation Number 326
That reminds me that she isn't here—
no, I was aware that she
wasn't around the entire time.
That's why I assumed
she was in my shadow—
unlike Ononoki or Hachikuji,
Shinobu and I can
never be truly apart.
Animation Number 326
That reminds me that she isn't here—
no, I was aware that she
wasn't around the entire time.
That's why I assumed
she was in my shadow—
unlike Ononoki or Hachikuji,
Shinobu and I can
never be truly apart.
Animation Number 326
Through my shadow.
Through my heart—
Animation Number 326
We are connected.
Shinobu isn't...
忍が？
We can never be apart— essentially, this immediately means
that she is currently holing up in my shadow.
Animation Number 327
We can never be apart— essentially, this immediately means
that she is currently holing up in my shadow.
Animation Number 327
We can never be apart— essentially, this immediately means
that she is currently holing up in my shadow.
Animation Number 327
We can never be apart— essentially, this immediately means
that she is currently holing up in my shadow.
Animation Number 327
We can never be apart— essentially, this immediately means
that she is currently holing up in my shadow.
Animation Number 327
We can never be apart— essentially, this immediately means
that she is currently holing up in my shadow.
Animation Number 327
We can never be apart— essentially, this immediately means
that she is currently holing up in my shadow.
Animation Number 327
We can never be apart— essentially, this immediately means
that she is currently holing up in my shadow.
Animation Number 327
We can never be apart— essentially, this immediately means
that she is currently holing up in my shadow.
Animation Number 327
We can never be apart— essentially, this immediately means
that she is currently holing up in my shadow.
Animation Number 327
We can never be apart— essentially, this immediately means
that she is currently holing up in my shadow.
Animation Number 327
We can never be apart— essentially, this immediately means
that she is currently holing up in my shadow.
Animation Number 327
—However.
However,
Animation Number 327
that is strange upon reflection.
But it's night.
（阿良々木）
だって 今は夜だ
Dawn is near, and it's not midnight anymore,
but this still clearly counts as night——
Animation Number 328
Dawn is near, and it's not midnight anymore,
but this still clearly counts as night——
Animation Number 328
Dawn is near, and it's not midnight anymore,
but this still clearly counts as night——
Animation Number 328
Dawn is near, and it's not midnight anymore,
but this still clearly counts as night——
Animation Number 328
Dawn is near, and it's not midnight anymore,
but this still clearly counts as night——
Animation Number 328
Dawn is near, and it's not midnight anymore,
but this still clearly counts as night——
Animation Number 328
Dawn is near, and it's not midnight anymore,
but this still clearly counts as night——
Animation Number 328
Dawn is near, and it's not midnight anymore,
but this still clearly counts as night——
Animation Number 328
Dawn is near, and it's not midnight anymore,
but this still clearly counts as night——
Animation Number 328
Dawn is near, and it's not midnight anymore,
but this still clearly counts as night——
Animation Number 328
Dawn is near, and it's not midnight anymore,
but this still clearly counts as night——
Animation Number 328
Dawn is near, and it's not midnight anymore,
but this still clearly counts as night——
Animation Number 328
There are no hints of impending dawn.
But why?
なのに どうして…
Why isn't Shinobu awake?
どうして 忍は起きていない？
"Why"? Devil boy, that's not something to ask me.
（斧乃木）どうしてって…
鬼のおにいちゃん
それを僕に聞かれても
Strong discomfort
Animation Number 331
I have difficulty answering... Or rather, because she hates me...
Strong discomfort
Animation Number 331
困る
というか そりゃまあ
あいつは僕が嫌いだから
It's true that Shinobu doesn't like you too much...
（阿良々木）
確かに 忍は お前のことを
好いてはいないけれど
...but she wouldn't hide in the shadows now of all times just because of that.
だけど それだけの理由で
この重大なときに 文字どおり
影を潜めたりはしないよ
She's not like that.
あいつは そういうヤツじゃない
You really trust her...
（斧乃木）信頼してるんだね
Then what does this mean?
じゃあ
どういうことだろう？
I think it's unlikely, but is she unconscious in the shadow or badly injured for some reason?
ありえないと思ったけど
影の中で
気絶しているのか
それとも 何らかの
理由で大けがをしたとか
I wonder if she could get badly injured in the shadow.
影の中にいて
大けがをするってことがあるのかな
It's like her own super-dimension in there, and she should be completely free from physical shocks and stimuli.
あそこは
忍の超空間みたいなものだし
そういう物理的なショックからは
無縁のはずなんだから…
My shadow in the moonlight is faint, but a shadow is a shadow——
Animation Number 344
She should be here.
It's strange that she isn't——
Animation Number 344
Ononoki-chan, this means I have to kiss you.
斧乃木ちゃん こうなったら
斧乃木ちゃんとキスをするしかない
How so?
どうなったら そうなった
Like yesterday, we have to approach Shinobu with that as motivation.
（阿良々木）昨日 そうしたように
その行為による動機で
忍にアプローチするしかないだろう
We have to kiss. Smooching with tongue is the only way!
キスしかない
ベロチューしかないんだ！
There is no other way
Animation Number 351
We have to kiss, whether we like it or not
No options!
Animation Number 351
If there's no other way, I will... But I kinda don't want to.
（斧乃木）
どうしてもって言うなら
そうするけど
なんか やだな
I don't want to.
Animation Number 353
Um, Araragi-san.
（八九寺）
あの 阿良々木さん！
Jealous, Hachikuji? If anything, you can be the girl I kiss.
何だ 八九寺　嫉妬か？
なんだったら キスする相手は
お前だっていいんだぜ
You should say so sooner if that's it.
それならそうと
早く言ってくれたら よかったのに
Araragi-san, please die.
死んでください 阿良々木さん
That's not it. Please wait.
あっ！　じゃなかった
待ってください 阿良々木さん
Why do I have to wait for my kiss with Ononoki-chan?
どうして 僕は
待たなければいけないんだ？
斧乃木ちゃんとのキッスを
No, Araragi-san, there are countless reasons...
（八九寺）
いえ 阿良々木さん
その理由は
無数にありますけれど
But before that, still, about Shinobu-san...
しかし その前に
それ以前に
忍さんのことなんですが
In other words, she's not in your shadow?
つまり… 影の中に
いないんですよね？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Right now, she's...
あの方 今
No, I don't think she's gone...
いや いないってわけじゃ…
Maybe she's sleeping
Animation Number 372
Maybe she's unconscious...
Devil boy, a moment...
（斧乃木）鬼のおにいちゃん
少し…
Ononoki-chan...
斧乃木ちゃん…
Quiet. I'm searching now.
（斧乃木）
黙って　今 調べてるから
I'm seeking...
探ってるから
I just waited.
Animation Number 379
For something like an answer.
いない
Not here.
At last
Animation Number 381
she said
with a plain voice
Animation Number 381
She's not here.
いない
Animation Number 383
I saw it then. How the "darkness" overlapped Araragi-san's shadow.
あのとき 私は見ました
Void
“くらやみ”が
阿良々木さんの影に重なったのを
Perhaps it was then that Shinobu-san got swallowed by that "darkness"?
ひょっとすると
そのときに忍さんは
あの“くらやみ”に
のまれたのではないでしょうか
It's really only a "perhaps," but...
本当に
“ひょっとすると”なんですけど…
（阿良々木）
あっ… 忍が のまれた？
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Shinobu was swallowed by that "darkness"...
あの〝くらやみ〞に？
No way...
そんな…
No, I don't think so.
いや
それは ないと思うな
Void
If she really was swallowed by it, devil boy would completely lose his vampiric nature.
仮に怪異殺しが
あれに のまれたのだとすれば
鬼のおにいちゃんは
吸血鬼性を完全に失うはずなんだ
He'd be a normal human.
ただの人間に戻るはずなんだ
But that didn't happen.
けれど そうなっていない
That isn't true...
Animation Number 401
No, but can you really tell whether or not I've lost my vampiric nature, Ononoki-chan?
いや でも 僕が吸血鬼性を
失っているか いないかなんて
ちゃんと判別できるのか？
As a familiar.
Animation Number 402
As an aberration.
Void
斧乃木ちゃんには
No, even you can easily distinguish whether you have.
（斧乃木）いや 単純な判別なら
鬼のおにいちゃんにだって
できるはずだよ
Because you can see Hachikuji-san right now, right?
だって 鬼のおにいちゃんには 今
八九寺さんが見えているんだろ？
Yeah.
If you can clearly see an aberration...
Void
（斧乃木）
怪異である八九寺さんが
しっかり見えているということは
...you haven't lost your vampiric nature.
鬼のおにいちゃんは吸血鬼性を
なくしていないということだよ
I see her. I can see her.
（阿良々木）
見える… 見えている
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
She is surely there.
確かにいる
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
That she
Animation Number 412
is not inside my shadow now
is indisputable.
Animation Number 412
I see...
そうか
She hasn't disappeared. But in this situation...
怪異殺しは消滅してはいない
Void
ただし この状況
...it's better to assume your pairing has been severed.
鬼のおにいちゃんと
怪異殺しのペアリングは
切れていると思ったほうがいい
The pairing's been severed?
ペアリングが切れている？
To be more precise, it could be that the pairing was eradicated.
（斧乃木）
より正確に言うならば
ペアリングが消滅した
ということなのかもしれない
Because that "darkness" overlapped your shadow.
あの“くらやみ”が
影に重なったことによってね
Shadow
Animation Number 419
Shadow Tag
The worst shadow tag ever
Animation Number 419
Void
If contact with my shadow back then broke the pairing...
（阿良々木）
あそこで影を踏まれたことで
もしも
ペアリングが切られたとして
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
If so, what then?
だとすれば
どういうことになるんだ？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Void
In other words, Shinobu is no longer tied to my shadow, right?
それって つまり 忍は もう
僕の影には
縛られなくなったってことだよな
If so...
だとすると…
Most likely, we left Aberration Killer behind at that location.
恐らくは 僕たちは怪異殺しを
あの場に置き去りに
してきたことになるだろうね
You've got to be kidding. Then I left Shinobu behind right where that unknown "darkness" is?
冗談じゃねえぜ…
じゃあ 僕は 忍を
あの正体不明の
“くらやみ”のもとに
置き去りにしてきちまった
っていうのかよ
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Please calm down, Araragi-san.
落ち着いてください 阿良々木さん
No time to get discouraged.
Animation Number 431
Don't blame yourself. Ononoki-san said so too.
自分を責めないでください
斧乃木さんが
おっしゃっていたじゃないですか
The fact that you can see me means that Shinobu-san is still alive.
あなたに私が
見えているということは つまり
忍さんは
生存中ということなんですから
We have to meet up with her.
Animation Number 432
I want to apologize to her.
I want to apologize.
Animation Number 432
This isn't the worst-case scenario.
最悪の事態ではありません
Though I don't know
Animation Number 433
whether it will cheer me up.
I still want to apologize.
Animation Number 433
Right. That's true.
そうだな… 確かに そうだ
I want to see her.
Animation Number 434
I won't forgive it.
Animation Number 435
How dare it?
How dare it do that to Shinobu——
Animation Number 435
Let's head down. I have to hurry to her.
山を下りよう
早く忍と合流しないと
I know how you feel, but don't be impatient.
（斧乃木）
気持ちは分かるけど
鬼のおにいちゃん
焦らないでよ
Damn it
Animation Number 438
I can't think straight
My actions are random and hasty
Animation Number 438
We should head down, but we need to contact my master before we reunite with Aberration Killer.
山を下りるというのは賛成だけども
怪異殺しと合流するより先に
おねえちゃんと連絡を取るべきだ
Oh, right...
ああ… そうか
Sequence
Animation Number 440
The optimal sequence
We need it
Animation Number 440
Well, in any case, we should move from here with your "Unlimited Rulebook," secession version.
まあ いずれにしても
斧乃木ちゃんのアンリミテッド･
ルールブック 離脱版で
ここから移動だよな
Yellow Scene
Animation Number 'none'
No, you're mistaken.
Yellow Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（斧乃木）
いや それは違う
鬼のおにいちゃん
Yellow Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Unfortunately, I can't use "Unlimited Rulebook," secession version.
残念ながら アンリミテッド･
ルールブック 離脱版は
もう使えないよ
Why?
え？　どうして…
Your broken pairing means at the very least...
（斧乃木）
怪異殺しとの
ペアリングが
切れているということは
...that you're not immortal right now.
少なくとも
今のあなたは
不死身ではない
That's why you couldn't handle that "secession" earlier.
だからこそ さっきの離脱に
鬼のおにいちゃんは
耐えられなかったんだ
You've gotten weaker. I'm not talking about just "Unlimited Rulebook," secession version either.
弱くなってるんだよ
鬼のおにいちゃんは 今
アンリミテッド･ルールブック
離脱版だけのことじゃない
It's best to assume you can't do reckless things like in the past two months.
ここ２か月くらいしてきたような
むちゃは
何もできないと思ったほうがいい
Animation Number 458
Ononoki-chan phrased it as getting weaker. To be precise, that's incorrect.
（阿良々木）
“弱くなっている”
と… 斧乃木ちゃんは表現したが
それは正確に言うと正しくない
It's not "getting weaker." It's "reverting to normal."
弱くなったのではなく
元に戻りつつあるのだと言うべきだ
My vampiric nature's not gone. It's lessened.
吸血鬼性は
なくなってこそいないが落ちている
My immortality isn't gone either. It's lessened.
不死身度も また
なくなってこそいないが落ちている
The breeze won't push me over.
Animation Number 460
Probably.
The situation is gradually deteriorating.
Animation Number 460
But on the other hand, is Shinobu's vampiric nature increasing?
（阿良々木）
だけど これは忍のほうは逆に
吸血鬼度が上がっている
ってことになるのかな
With the pairing broken, conversely...
ペアリングが切れることで
相対的に
No, I think it's decreased even on her side. Like a chain reaction.
（斧乃木）
いや あっちはあっちで
吸血鬼度が下がっているだろうね
連鎖的にね
That's how your relationship works.
あなたたちの関係は
そういうふうになってるんだよ
Yes.
Animation Number 465
That's what the idea was.
Animation Number 466
So it's not just me. Shinobu's condition will only worsen.
（阿良々木）
つまり 僕のほうだけじゃない
忍のほうの状況も
悪くなる一方なのだ
But I need to calm down. It's not over yet. The story is still continuing.
だが 落ち着け
まだ終わったわけじゃあない
物語は 続いているのだ
Koyomi   Monologue / Thoughts
Animation Number 472
Animation Number 479
Stand By
You said texts were a way to reach Kagenui-san, right?
影縫さんにはメールでも
連絡は取れるんだったよな？
What do I write?
（阿良々木）
文面は何にすればいい？
Our secret password and an encrypted text that says I await contact.
（斧乃木）合言葉を
それと
連絡を待つって意味の暗号を
Send
Sending
This is in passing, but I decided to text Senjougahara, Hanekawa, Karen, and Tsukihi that I was all right.
（阿良々木）
ついでと言っては なんだが
戦場ヶ原(せんじょうがはら)と羽川(はねかわ)
それに 火憐(かれん)と月火(つきひ)に
僕の無事を知らせるメールを
送っておくことにした
I don't want to make them worry.
Animation Number 486
Senjougahara Hi
No Subject
Won't be home for a
while. Don't vorry.
Send
Won't be home for a
while. Don't vorry.
Senjougahara Hitagi
No Subject
Won't be home for a
while. Don't vorry.
Send
Sending
Hehe
Animation Number 487
Stand By
I've become such a caring man.
Animation Number 489
Araragi-san.
阿良々木さん！
What, Hachikuji?
何だ？　八九寺
I hate to say this after you sent it, but the text you sent them...
（八九寺）
送信されたあとで言うのも
なんなんですが
羽川さんたちに送ったメール
文面が…
You mistyped and had "dont vorry."
Senjougahara Hi
No Subject
Won't be home for a
while. Don't vorry.
Send
“心配すれな”になっていました
Won't be home for a
while. Don't vorry.
What's with telling me just after I sent it!
（阿良々木）
本当に 送信されたあとで言うのも
なんだよ！
23rd of August
Devil boy, how do the bars look on your phone?
（斧乃木）
鬼のおにいちゃん
携帯電話のアンテナは
どう？
Animation Number 503
Stand By
No Reply
Animation Number 504
（阿良々木）うん
Weak as always. Better than no reception, I guess.
相変わらず かぼそいな
圏外じゃないだけ
まだ よかったが…
We were lucky before.
（斧乃木）
さっきは 運が良かったんだね
I dunno. No reply from Kagenui-san, it seems.
（阿良々木）
どうだろう 影縫さんからの返信は
ないみたいだぞ
Hmm... Maybe it's better to call at this point. Let's ask someone in one of these houses.
（斧乃木）ふむ… じゃあ もう
いっそ電話をかけたほうが
いいかもしれないね
その辺の民家に お邪魔して
Weak cell-phone reception doesn't mean there aren't landlines.
携帯電話のアンテナは弱かろうと
固定電話が
ないわけじゃないだろうし
If her work's done, do calls reach Kagenui-san directly?
もしも 仕事が終わってたら
電話は直通で影縫さんに届くのか？
Well, sometimes they do, and sometimes they don't... It's pretty random.
（斧乃木）
まあ そういうときもあれば
そうでないときもあるというか…
割と適当だよ
Random?
適当って…
It's her theory that it's dangerous to create patterns in lifestyle.
（斧乃木）
生活にパターンを作ると
危険だというのが
おねえちゃんの持論でね
That so?
Animation Number 514
Come to think of it, Oshino tried to prevent creating patterns in everyday life too.
（阿良々木）
生活にパターンを
作らないようにしているのは
そういえば
忍野(おしの)のヤツも同じだったな
What, is it some global rule among the previous occult studies club members?
なんだろう
かつてのオカルト研究会の仲間の
共通ルールみたいなものなのかね
By the way, Gaen Izuko was apparently a member of that club too.
（斧乃木）臥煙伊豆湖も
そのサークルの
メンバーだったらしいよ
そういえば
Really? Then she knows Oshino too.
（阿良々木）え？　そうなの？
じゃあ 忍野の
知り合いでもあるんだ その人
Oshino and Kaiki... Some strange ties.
忍野と貝木(かいき)の…
なんか 変な縁だな
I think she said she was an upperclassman... One with a horrible personality.
（斧乃木）
“先輩”って言ってたかな
おねえちゃんは
“性格の悪い先輩だ”って
Damn right he is.
Animation Number 526
Does their circle have a single decent human being?
Excuse me, we're travelers. We'd like some food...
（阿良々木）
すいません！　旅の者です
何か 食べ物を下さい
No, um...
じゃなかった　えっと…
Can we borrow your phone for a bit?
電話を貸してもらえませんか？
I have to make a phone call, whatever it takes.
Animation Number 535
I have to meet up with my partner.
My life-long partner.
Animation Number 535
Excuse me, we're travelers...
すいません！
旅の者です
Yes, yes!
（臥煙）はいは〜い
Sorry to make you wait.
（臥煙）お待たせ
Um...
えっと…
Sorry to make you wait. Though I'm the one who's been waiting.
（臥煙）
つうか〜 お待たせっつうか
待ってたのは私のほうだけどね
Nice to meet you. I'm Gaen Izuko. A young lady who knows everything.
はじめまして 私は臥煙伊豆湖
何でも知ってる おねえさんだ
Preview
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
Karen here!
（火憐）火憐だぜ！
（月火）月火だよ！
And Tsukihi!
I'm Tsukihi!
Together, we're the Fire Sisters!
We're the Fire Sisters!!
Devil!
（火憐･月火）
２人合わせて
ファイヤーシスターズ
Something awesome just appeared!
Darkness
I don't think you should touch it.
（月火）
早いもので
Monogatari Series Second Season is approaching 20 episodes at a fast pace.
〝物語〞シリーズ
セカンドシーズンも
通算20話が見えてきたね
（火憐）
いっそ このまま
40話までいっちゃうか！
While we're at it, why not reach 40?
We'll have gone through all light novels before then.
（月火）
原作
追い抜いちゃうよ？
That would the time for a Fire Sisters spin off, you idiot.
（火憐）
バカ そのときこそ
Eh! You know of a way to suppress it?
I know everything~
ファイヤーシスターズの
スピンオフだろ！
Preview Quiz!
（月火）予告編クイズ！
（火憐）クイズ！
Quiz!
Christmas day is on December 25, right?
（月火）
クリスマスといえば
12月25日ですが
25 it is.
（火憐）
25日だな
Then Christmas Tree day is on December 7.
（月火）
クリスマスツリーの日は
12月７日なんだよ
Neighborhood
Beauty contest
What the...?
（火憐）
なんで？
Eh, why is that?
Because people spend 18 days decorating their Christmas tree, that's why.
（月火）
クリスマスツリーの
日から
クリスマスの日までの
18日間の間に
人々は
クリスマスツリーを
飾りつけるんじゃ
ないかな
（火憐）
手間かかってんな
Decorations take time...
I'm quite confident
Parading
Skin!
Will they be okay...
Now time for the quiz: Hina-matsuri takes place on March 3,
（月火）
ここからがクイズです
ひな祭りといえば
３月３日ですが
then what day does it make Hinama Tree day?
では
ひなまツリーの日は
何日でしょう？
March 7?
（火憐）
３月７日か？
Nope, still March 3.
（月火）
３月３日ですけどね
Next Time
Shinobu Time Part 4
Next time! Onimonogatari Episode 4!
（火憐･月火）
次回「鬼物語 第４話
しのぶタイム 其ノ肆(そのよん)」
Shinobu Time, Part 4.
Of course not!
Vampire
Familiar
Ghost
It's called Hina-matsuri, but it's not really a festival.
（月火）
ひな祭りっていうほど
フェスティバル感
ないけどね
It's still better than Hinama Tree...
（火憐）
ツリー感は
もっとねえだろ